{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Mark the wrong option. Which of the following cause and effect behaviour in speed control is correct when field resistance is increased.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "  Decrease in flux ",
        "b": "Increase in armature current",
        "c": "Increase in EMF",
        "d": "Decrease in speed"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Small DC motors have best speed control by _________",
      "answers": {
        "a": " armature voltage control",
        "b": "field resistance control",
        "c": "any of the methods",
        "d": "none of the mentioned"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Consider the following statements regarding speed control of dc motor.<br/>1)Field control method is used to vary the speed of the motor above the rated speed<br/>2)Armature resistance control method is used to vary speed below or above the rated speed.<br/>which one is correct?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1 only",
        "b": "1 and 2 both",
        "c": " 2 only",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The torque limit of speed for a shunt motor _________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "remains constant till base speed",
        "b": "remains constant after base speed",
        "c": "varies linearly after base speed",
        "d": "varies inversely till base speed"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The most economical method of electrical braking is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Plugging",
        "b": "Dynamic braking with sel-exitation",
        "c": "Regenerative braking",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "Speed control by ward-leonard method gives uniform speed variation",
      "answers": {
        "a": "In one direction",
        "b": "In both direction",
        "c": "Below normal speed",
        "d": "Above normal speed"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },	
	
	
	{
      "question": "For a dc shunt motor if exitation is changed,then",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Torque will remain constant",
        "b": "Torque will change but power will remain constant",
        "c": "Torque and Power both will change",
        "d": "All the torque,speed and power will change"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	{
      "question": "for driving a dc motor, ac must be converted to dc and then only fed to dc motor armature for its speed control ",
	  "answers": {
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False"
        
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	{
      "question": "A 250-V dc series motor has armature and series-field resistances o f 0.25 fl and 0.15 fl respectively.Calculate the current for developing a torque o f 80 Nm at 1200 rpm.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "30A",
        "b": "43.2A",
        "c": "15A",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
	
	
	
	
	
	{
	 "question": " With the increase in temperature, the speed of series and shunt motor will",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Increase, decrease",
        "b": "Decrease, increase",
        "c": "Increase, increase",
        "d": "Decrease, decrease,"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
